LI Yefeng (李烨锋)

li3915@purdue.edu +86 13238191225 / +852 56895775

Research Interests

My research interests lie in the broad area of Programming Languages and Software Systems. I am interested in formal verification for distributed programming and for compilation, type systems, proof assistants, functional programming, and so on. I hope to develope rigorously founded theories and tools at the service of reliable software.

EDUCATION

Purdue University

Doctor of Philosophy student in Computer Science

West Lafayette, IN, USA

Hong Kong University of Science and Technology (HKUST)

Master of Philosophy in Computer Science and Engineering Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Engineering | Minor in Robotics Hong Kong S.A.R. Sept. 2018 – June 2020 Sept. 2014 – June 2018

RESEARCH PROJECTS

Manifoldness Preserving Contraction

M.Phil. thesis, advised by Prof. Quan Long

VisGraph Lab, CSE, HKUST Aug. 2018 – May 2020

• Designed a new contraction method that guarantees manifold output given a manifold input using augmentation and the separation of singularities. It can be applied to geometry processing as a replacement to the conventional contraction operation which may destroy topology and produce imperfect results.

Triangle mesh simplification

Advised by Prof. Quan Long

VisGraph Lab, CSE, HKUST Aug. 2018 – May 2020

- Used new contraction techniques to improve triangle mesh simplification wherein traditional methods fail to effectively restrict the destruction of input topology.
- Facilitated the parallelization in the construction of Levels-of-Detail of 3D models using 2D-projection of tile boundaries.

Centralized Wireless Local Area Networks

HKUST

Undergraduate final-year thesis, advised by Prof. Brahim Bensaou

Sept. 2017 - Mar. 2018

• Specified a centralization protocol for Wireless LANs as an (software-defined networking) extension atop CSMA/CA to explore the improvement of resource utilization in dense indoor networks. It was partially implemented in C based on hostapd's source code and experimented on OpenWrt embedded Linux system.

Photograph capturing with drones

VisGraph Lab, CSE, HKUST

Undergraduate Research Opportunity Program, advised by Prof. Quan Long

Aug. - Nov. 2016

• Investigated in the application of Computer Vision and Graphics for Android devices as remote controls for drones, with a focus on human-drone interaction. An Android application was built to retrieve data from a geography database and visualize useful information on the screen according to the vision of the drone.

Professional Experience

Everest Innovation Technology (merged into Apple Inc.)

Researcher & Software Developer

Shenzhen & Hong Kong, China June – Aug. 2019

- Triangle mesh processing: Transferred novel geometry processing techniques into *Altizure*, a world-class cloud-based 3D reconstruction platform; developed efficient mesh processing program in C++.
- ZRPC: Participated in the development of ZRPC, an RPC distributed computing framework, in Go.
- Data management and visualization: Developed a photographic data validation, management, and visualization desktop application in JavaScript.

Dash Serviced Suites

Part-time JavaScript Developer

Hong Kong Feb. – May 2018

• Web development: Worked on the Web interface, API, and database management of *DASH2*, an online marketplace Web application by the startup company.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Department of Computer Science and Engineering, HKUST

Teaching Assistant

Hong Kong 2018 – 2019

- COMP1021: Introduction to Computer Science, Fall 2019
- COMP3311: Database Management Systems, Fall 2018

Extracurricular Activities

ACM SIGPLAN Symposium on Principles of Programming Languages

Student Volunteer

New Orleans, LA, USA Jan. 2020

• Supported event organization.

RoboMaster Robotics Competition

Mechanical/Computer Engineer

Shenzhen, China *Feb. – Aug. 2017*

• Co-designed the mechanical structure of *Hero*, the main-force in this multi-robot contest, for RoboMaster HKUST team. Our Hero robot was controlled remotely, capable of capturing, storing and shooting bullets, and climbing onto stairs with telescopic legs.

Chinese Folk-Art Society, HKUST

IT Secretary, Executive Committee

Hong Kong *Feb. 2015 – Feb. 2016*

- Independently built the official website of our society and developed a Web application in JavaScript to assist the hosting of a knowledge competition named *Who is Still Standing*.
- Took charge of photographing and Internet platform promotions.
- Organized trips to the Yangzi, China and Dragon's Back, Hong Kong.